第一个示例是端到端的 RAG 聊天机器人。
The first example we'll work on is an end-to-end RAG chatbot.
让我们使用 Claude Code 来探索代码库。
Let's use Claude Code to explore the code base.
在开始使用 Claude Code
Before we start using Claude Code
为我们编写大量代码之前，
to write lots of code for us,
先聊聊如何使用这个工具
let's talk about how we can use this tool
来快速熟悉大型代码库。
to get up to speed on larger code bases.
这里有一个应用，我可以就 DeepLearning.AI
Right here, I have an application where I can chat with Claude
的课程材料与 Claude 进行交流。
about course materials from Deep Learning AI.
试着询问课程大纲。例如：
So let's try asking an outline of a course. For example, what
MCP 构建上下文丰富的 AI 应用的大纲是什么？
is the outline of the MCP Build Rich-Context AI Apps with Anthropic.
我们将看到我得到了一个
We'll see here that I'll get a
非常详细的回复，
response with quite a bit of detail
包括每一小节的介绍及其描述。
around the lessons and descriptions for each of those lessons.
考虑到这一点，让我们看看如何
With that in mind, let's see how we can get
快速了解支撑该应用的底层代码。
up to speed on the underlying code that powers this application.
回到 VS Code，我打开了
Back in VS Code, I have
这里的终端，我准备
the terminal open here and I'm going
只需输入 claude 并按回车键
to hop into Claude Code just
即可进入 Claude Code。
by typing in claude and pressing enter.
在这个应用中，我可以开始与我的代码库对话。
In this application, I can start chatting with my codebase.
我将从一个宏观的问题开始，
So I'm going to start with a high-level question just to
以此获得代码库概览。
give me an overview of the codebase.
我们将看到 Claude Code 代理化地搜索
What we're going to see Claude Code do is agentically search
代码库，找出一些最重要的文件，
over the codebase, figure out some of the most important files
并描述这个应用程序中发生了什么。
and give me a description of what's happening in this application.
它不会去搜索每一个文件，
Instead of searching through each individual file,
而是通过代理化搜索找到最相关的文件。
we're going to agentically search and find the most relevant ones.
在这里，我们将获得有关架构、
So here we're going to get some information about
关键组件、一些功能的信息，
the architecture, the key components, some of the features,
现在，如果我想深入了解
and now if there are particular
特定的内容，我可以轻松做到。
things I want to dig into, I can easily do that.
我还可以问其他更高层次的问题，比如
I can also ask other higher level questions like how
“这些文档是如何处理的？”
are these documents processed?
在这个应用中，我们使用 RAG 技术
In this application, we're using Retrieval Augmented Generation
来获取这些课程的信息。
to fetch information about these courses.
如果我想了解该过程的更多信息，
If I want to get more information about that process,
可以提出类似的问题。
I can ask a question like this one.
我们常说，Claude Code 不仅是你身边的
We like to say that Claude Code is a fantastic
一名优秀工程师，
engineer alongside you,
更是一个出色的解释者。
but it's an even better explainer.
因此，当你开始熟悉新的代码库或
So as you're getting up to speed with new codebases,
新的数据集时。请先尝试让 Claude Code
new data sets. First, start using Claude Code
为你解释事情，
as a way to explain things to you,
这样当你要求它编写代码时，
so that when you ask it to write code,
你就能更好地理解发生了什么。
you can have a better understanding of what's going on.
在这里，我们可以看到代码库中的
Here we can see the sources in the
源代码，它们实际上是将文本分割成块，
code base that are actually splitting text into chunks,
添加课程上下文以及存储课程元数据。
that are adding lesson context and that are storing course metadata.
这种快速熟悉代码库的能力，
This ability to quickly get up to speed with a code base,
尤其是当你可能不
especially when you might not be
熟悉底层技术或语言时，
familiar with the underlying technology or language,
是非常有价值的。与其
is exceptionally valuable. Instead of
导航到每个文件夹并弄清楚发生了什么，
navigating to each of these folders and figuring out what's going on,
我们可以提出更具体的问题，甚至让它
we can ask more specific questions and even get diagrams
为我们生成图表和可视化效果。
and visualizations made for us.
所以，我问 Claude 的第一件事
So the first thing I'll ask Claude
就是：追踪处理用户查询
is to trace the process of handling a user's query
从前端到后端的整个过程。
from front end to back end.
你可以想象，你可能对技术栈的
You can imagine you might have some limited knowledge
某一部分了解有限，或者
in one of the parts of the stack or
不熟悉整个流程。
you're not familiar with how this is all happening.
Claude Code 会在这里
So Claude Code is going to
提供非常有用的信息。
give us quite some useful information here.
观察 Claude Code 工作时，最有用的
What's useful when you're seeing Claude Code work
是它能为你提供一份待办清单，
is its ability to give you a bit of a to-do list,
这样你就能开始理解
so you can start to understand
正在发生的事情。在任何时间点，
what's happening. At any point in time,
你都可以按 Esc 键并引导 Claude Code
you can press escape and guide Claude Code
遵循另一组待办事项，
to follow a different set of to-dos,
但在这种情况下，我觉得它的做法很不错。
but in this case, I feel pretty good about what it's doing.
它将开始从前端追踪，跟踪 API 端点，
It's going to start tracing from the frontend, start following API endpoints,
分析我们的 RAG 系统，
analyze our Retrieval Augmented Generation system,
然后搞清楚如何实际生成响应。
and then figure out how to actually generate the response.
它正在读取处理这些特定任务的相关文件，
It's reading the appropriate files that are handling these particular tasks
并完成清单以提供一份强有力的总结。
and finishing up its list to give us a powerful summary.
在这个环境中，
As we're in this environment,
我们可以留在 VS Code 内部，或者
we can stay within VS Code or open
在独立的终端实例中打开 Claude Code。
up Claude Code in its own dedicated terminal instance.
这完全取决于你。一旦完成，
That's completely up to you as you're working in this application.
我们可以看到一条
Once it's done, we can see a
非常详细的路径。
very detailed path for what's happening here.
我不但可以逐步阅读这些步骤，
Not only can I read each of these step-by-step,
甚至可以要求 Claude 将其写入文件，
I can even ask Claude to write this to a file,
我看到了前端 JavaScript 的细节，
but I'm seeing in quite a bit
到达后端后
of detail what's happening on the front end
发生了什么，
with some JavaScript, what happens once that reaches my back end,
RAG 系统在做什么，
what the Retrieval Augmented Generation system is doing,
响应是如何生成的。最后，
how I'm generating a response. Finally,
它是如何搜索向量数据库、
how I'm searching through my vector database,
如何过滤必要信息、获取响应，
how I'm filtering what's necessary, getting a response back,
并最终发送给用户的。
and then finally, sending that to the user.
这个应用中有很多事情在发生。
There's a lot that's going on in this application.
我可以利用 Claude
And I can use Claude to
深入研究其中的任何部分。
dive deeper into any of those pieces.
假设我通过可视化学习的效果最好。
But let's just say I learn best from visualizations.
那么让我们要求 Claude 画一个示意图
So let's ask Claude to draw a diagram
来展示这个流程。
that illustrates this flow.
我们可以要求 Claude 绘制网页可视化的图表，
We can ask Claude to draw diagrams
也可以要求 ASCII 艺术。
for web visualizations. We can ask for ASCII art.
让我们看看 Claude 凭自身的智能和对
But let's see what Claude comes up with
应用运行方式的了解会做出什么。
with its own intelligence and knowledge of how the application works.
好了，让我们看看 Claude Code 给出了什么。
So let's see what Claude code has come up with.
我们得到了一个非常漂亮的示意图，
We've got a really nice diagram here
展示了分步过程。
showing us the step-by-step process.
（纠正：它确实能创建这些视觉图表）
So it can't create these visual diagrams.
我们总是可以要求它使用 D3.js
We could always ask it to use some something like D3.js
或 Recharts 之类的工具。但就在这里，
or recharts if we want something like a web application.
我们得到了一个非常棒的图表。
But we can see right here, we've got a really nice diagram.
从前端向后端发送请求，
From the front end, making a request to the back end,
调用必要的函数，
calling the necessary functions,
如果涉及历史记录则生成必要的响应，
generating the response necessary if there's any history involved,
直接通过系统提示词、工具和查询
talking directly to the large language model
与大语言模型对话，
with our system prompts and our tools and a query,
确定下一步去向，
figuring out where to go next,
使用 Chroma DB 搜索向量数据库，获取结果
searching through our vector database using Chroma DB, getting back results
并格式化，最后发送给模型生成最终响应。
formatting that, sending it to the model to produce a final response.
这其中涉及很多细节。
There's quite a bit of detail that goes into this.
如果愿意，我们甚至可以为 Claude 增加额外的工具
And if we want, we can even augment Claude with additional tools
来生成我们想要的可视化效果。
for generating the visualizations that we want.
但开箱即用，能够快速高效地获取这些信息，
But out of the box, just getting this information quickly and efficiently
将帮助我们熟悉代码库，
is going to help us get up to speed with this
花费的时间只是过去的一小部分。
codebase in a fraction of time that we used to spend.
考虑到这一点，让我们问一个
So with that in mind, let's ask a
非常简单的问题：“我该如何运行
very simple question, how do I run
这个应用程序？”你可能遇到
this application? You might be in a situation
新技术或新想法。
where there's a new technology here, a new idea.
很简单，直接了解
Very simply, it's nice to just
如何运行是非常好的。
know how to get up and running.
我可以在这里看到 API 文档、
I can see here, my API documentation,
Web 界面，以及我需要的环境变量，
my web interface, and if there are any environment variables I need,
一切准备就绪。既然你已经了解了
I'm good to go. Now that you've gotten an idea
如何开始与 Claude Code 对话。
of how to just start talking to Claude Code.
让我们聊聊一些更强大的功能
Let's talk a little bit about some of the more powerful features
关于 Claude Code。
with Claude Code.
当你开始使用 Claude Code 处理应用时，
When you start working with an application in Claude Code,
我们建议你做的
one of the first things we
第一件事就是运行一个命令，
recommend you do is run a command
叫做 /init。
called /init.
你可以看到，当我输入斜杠时，
You can see here in Claude Code, when I add this slash,
会出现一个内置命令列表。
we have a list of many built-in commands that I can use.
/init 允许我初始化一个
/init allows me to initialize
包含代码库文档的 CLAUDE.md 文件。
a CLAUDE.md file with the codebase documentation.
CLAUDE.md 文件至关重要，
The CLAUDE.md file is mission critical
它为 Claude Code 引入了“记忆”，
for introducing memory for Claude Code,
使它知道如何最好地在你的代码库中工作。
so that it knows how best to work in your codebase.
CLAUDE.md 文件对于
The CLAUDE.md file is very useful
指定你希望如何运行任务非常有用。
for specifying how you want things to be run.
这可以是你的测试、Lint 检查，
This could be your tests, this could be your linting,
以及任何你希望 Claude 保留的长期记忆，
and any long-term memory that you want Claude to have
每当你处理该特定项目时。
each time you're working with Claude Code for this particular project.
/init 不会让你从头开始制作，
Instead of making this from scratch, /init
它会分析代码库，
is going to analyze the codebase
从宏观层面上弄清楚它应该了解的内容，
to figure out at a high level what it should know about
每当你处理此应用时。
each time you're working with this application.
你可以创建三种不同的 CLAUDE.md 文件，
There are three different CLAUDE.md files that you can make,
就像最左边这个
like the one generated with /init
由 /init 生成的一样。
all the way here on the left.
这个文件存放在你的应用中。你可以在
This CLAUDE.md file lives in your application. You can
嵌套的子文件夹中拥有多个此类文件。
have many of them in nested sub folders.
但它是与团队成员共享的，
But this is shared with other
并提交到版本控制系统中。
engineers and committed to your version control.
另一个选择是，如果你有个人指令
Another option is if you have personal instructions
和自定义设置（比如针对你的编辑器环境
and customizations, think specific for your editing environment
和终端环境），可以放在 CLAUDE.local.md 文件中。
and terminal environment, you can put that in a CLAUDE.local.md file.
这个文件被 git 忽略，不会与其他工程师共享。
This is git ignored and not shared with other engineers.
最后，在你的主目录下的
Finally, in your home directory, in the
.claude 文件夹中，你可以添加一个 CLAUDE.md，
.claude folder, you can add a CLAUDE.md
你可以把它看作是机器上
and you can think of this like a
所有项目的全局 claude.md。
global claude.md for all projects on your machine.
如果你希望 Claude 在你构建的各种项目中
This is helpful if you want Claude to follow instructions across
都遵循指令，这会很有帮助。
a wide range of projects that you build with Claude Code.
我们可以让 Claude Code 查找不同的文件，
We can go ahead and allow Claude Code to find different
以便它知道如何最好地创建 CLAUDE.md 文件。
files so that it knows how best to create this CLAUDE.md file.
该文件旨在被添加到
This CLAUDE.md file is meant to be
你当前的 git 项目中，
added to your current git project and
并与其他团队成员共享。
shared with other team members.
随着更多人参与代码库，
As more individuals work on the codebase,
他们可以补充这个 CLAUDE.md 文件，
they can add to this CLAUDE.md file,
如果你需要针对后端、前端或文档
and you can even nest CLAUDE.md files
提供更具体的指令，你甚至可以
in subdirectories if you need
在子目录中嵌套
more specific instructions for things like the backend
CLAUDE.md 文件。
or frontend or our docs that we have here.
在 VS Code 中使用像
What's really nice about using a tool
Claude Code 这样的工具，非常棒的一点是，
like Claude Code with Visual Studio Code,
当我看到文件发生更改时，
is that as I see changes to files,
我可以在编辑器中直观地看到它们。
I can see those visually in my editor.
每当我在 Claude Code 中使用工具时，
And anytime that I am using a tool in Claude Code,
它都会向我请求许可。
it's going to ask me for permissions.
这种“人在回路”的机制非常重要，
This mission critical human in the loop is really important
尤其是在你刚上手时，
when you get up and running,
如果你不需要 Claude 每次都询问你，
and if you don't need Claude to ask you every single time,
可以随时选择第二个选项（自动接受）。我们将
can always use this second option. We'll
继续自动接受这些编辑，
go ahead and auto accept those edits
你会看到已经为我们创建了一个 CLAUDE.md 文件。
and we'll see that a CLAUDE.md file has been created for us.
为了快速带你浏览一下，
To give you a quick walk through,
我们可以看到它给出了项目概览、
we can see it's given us a
关键技术、架构概览、
project overview, key technologies, an architectural overview,
一个精美的小图表、核心组件等。
a nice little diagram here, some core components.
还有更多内容。如果我们想更改
and much more. If we want things to change
这个 CLAUDE.md，可以轻松实现。
to this particular CLAUDE.md, we can easily do so.
随着它继续搜索代码库，
As it continues searching the codebase,
它会在这里对 CLAUDE.md 进行额外的编辑，
it makes additional edits here to my CLAUDE.md
并给我一份已完成工作的总结。
and gives me a summary of what's been done.
在 VS Code 中使用 Claude Code 时，
When I'm using a tool like Claude Code in VS Code,
我能够指定我所在的
I have the ability to specify which
文件，甚至获取
file I'm in and even get information
有关特定行的信息。
about particular lines.
为了设置这一点，我将使用 /ide 命令。
To set this up, I'm going to use the /ide command.
我可以看到我这里
and I can see right here
已经连接到了 Visual Studio Code。
that I'm connected with Visual Studio Code.
现在在 VS Code 中，我们可以看到
Now that I'm in Visual Studio Code, we can see right here
一旦我访问一个文件，
that the second that I visit a file,
它就会在这里打上标签。
it's tagged right here for what's going on.
这为 Claude Code 提供了我所在文件
This gives Claude Code the right context
的正确上下文，如果有
for which file I'm in and if there are questions
关于该文件的问题，Claude Code 就能
I have about that file, it makes it easier
更轻松地识别。
for Claude Code to identify that.
如果我以后想对
If I ever want to make any changes
CLAUDE.md 文件进行更改，可以手动编写。
to my CLAUDE.md file, I can manually write that if I'd like.
或者我可以使用一个方便的命令，
Or I can use a handy command
输入这个井号键（#）
to go ahead and use this pound key
并直接添加至记忆。
and directly add to memory.
我会说：始终使用 UV
So I'm just going to say here, always use UV.
来运行服务器，不要直接使用 pip。
to run the server, do not use pip directly.
这是 Python 生态系统中的一个包管理器，
This is a package manager in the Python ecosystem
我想确保 Claude 不会搞混。
and I want to make sure that Claude doesn't get confused.
当我使用这个快捷方式时，可以看到有不同的地方
When I use this shortcut, we can see there are different places
可以保存这些记忆。
where this memory can be saved.
我们提到过“项目记忆”，
We mentioned there is the Project memory
它是包含在 git 中供团队所有人使用的。
that is included in git for everyone on your team to use.
我们有“本地记忆”，它是被 git 忽略的，
We have local memory that is gitignored
但对你个人开发很有用。
but just useful for you as the developer.
还有“用户记忆”，它适用于
and then User memory that is applicable
你使用 Claude Code 的所有项目。
to all projects you use with Claude Code.
对于这个，我将更新项目记忆。
For this one, I'll just go ahead and update the project memory.
我可以看到我已经完成了更改。
I can see here, I've made that change.
如果我查看 CLAUDE.md，会看到这里
And if I look in my CLAUDE.md, I'll see right here,
提到了使用 UV
I have some mentions to using UV
以确保操作正确。
to make sure that I'm doing that correctly.
如果我想更具体一点，我还可以说：
If I want to be more specific, I can also say,
确保使用 UV 管理所有依赖项。
make sure to use UV to manage all dependencies.
我会把它添加到 CLAUDE.md 中，
I'll add this to my CLAUDE.md and
我们可以看到它已经被添加了。
we'll see right here that it's been added.
如果我快速看一下这个文件，
If I take a quick look at this particular file,
任何提到依赖项的地方现在都包含了 UV。
we can see any mention of dependencies now includes UV.
我们谈到了一些 Claude Code 内置的
We spoke a little bit about some of the commands
命令，比如 /init（注意：视频中口误为 /emit）。
that are built into Claude Code like /emit.
这里还有几个有用的
There are a couple other useful
我想展示一下。
ones that I want to showcase here.
事实上，我们在本课程的后面
And in fact, we're going to see later on
会看到，我们甚至可以创建自己的命令。
in this course, we can even make our own.
第一个我想带你
One of the first ones I
了解的是 /help。
want to walk you through is /help.
它会立即向我显示所有命令的
This shows me right off the bat a quick description
简短描述和摘要。
of all the commands. and a quick summary.
这在你熟悉 Claude Code 时非常有用。
This is useful as you're getting up to speed with Claude code.
下一个我想展示的是 /clear 命令。
The next one I want to showcase is a command called /clear.
它允许你
What this allows you to do is
清除对话历史并从头开始。
clear the conversation history and start from scratch.
当你转换工作方向或构建新功能时，这非常有用。
This is very helpful as you shift gears and build new features.
这可以让你清空上下文窗口并重新开始。
This allows you to clear the context window and start fresh.
如果你想继续对话，
If you want to continue the conversation,
需要一个更小的上下文窗口，但仍
have a smaller context window, but still
希望保留已完成工作的摘要，
have a summary of what's been done,
我们还有 /compact 命令，
we also have this command /compact
它允许你清除历史，但保留摘要，
that allows you to clear the history, but keep a summary
这样你就可以在 Claude 了解之前工作的
so that you can build off with Claude having an idea
基础上继续构建。
of what was done before.
还有一个有用的命令是 Esc 键，它可以让
One more useful command is the escape key that allows you
你退出当前正在运行的任何命令。
to get out of whatever command you're in.
如果我正在尝试运行 /compact
So if I'm going and trying to do something like /compact
并想停止该过程，我随时可以按 Esc。
and I want to stop that process, I can always press escape.
如果我启动了一个过程让 Claude Code
If I start a process with Claude Code
解释代码库的内容。
to explain what is in the codebase.
如果我想停止该过程，Esc 键
If I want to stop that process, escape
将允许我中断并继续后续工作。
will allow me to interrupt and continue, onwards.
所以，如果你没有得到想要的东西，
So don't feel like you have to wait for
不要觉得必须等待 Claude Code。
Claude Code if you're not getting what you need.
在下一课中，我们将开始使用 Claude Code 构建功能、
In the next lesson, we'll start using Claude Code to build features,
添加文件、修改更改，并确保在此过程中
add to files, modify changes, and make sure
做正确的事情。
we're doing the right thing along the way.
在结束之前，Claude Code 最后一个
Before we hop off, one last useful piece with
有用的功能是它与 Git 的协作能力。
Claude Code is its ability to work with Git.
我对这个应用做了一些小的更改，
So I've made some small changes to this application,
我想添加并提交这些更改。
and I want to add and commit these changes.
不需要我手动编写
Instead of me manually have to write
Git 命令或撰写描述性的提交信息，
the Git commands, write a descriptive commit message,
我实际上可以让 Claude Code 为我们完成这项工作。
going to actually have Claude Code do that work for us.
非常棒的一点是 Claude Code 能够添加
And what's really nice is Claude Code's ability to add
并提交必要的命令。
and commit the necessary commands.
我将添加这个特定的文件，
I'll go ahead and add this particular file,
不仅提交，而且你可以看到，
not only commit, but you can see here,
我得到了一个非常描述清晰的提交信息。
I've got this really nice descriptive commit message.
当我们开始向 Claude Code 询问
That's incredibly useful as we start asking Claude Code
Git 的历史变更时，这非常有用。
about historical changes with git.
当我们将其推送到 GitHub 让
and when we push this to GitHub and
其他人阅读更改时，
other people are reading the changes
这都很有用。我们将进行添加和提交，
we made. So we'll add and commit
在下一节课中，我们将使用 Claude Code
and the next lesson, we'll use Claude Code
开始为我们编写大量的内容。
to start writing lots of things for us.